<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="playSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
    <body>
        <pg>
            <sp>
                NARRATOR:
            </sp> 
            <dialogue>
                I know you did so. You went to the first women's
            suffrage meetings, and you joined with Abby Kelly
            and Luoretia Mott and Frances Gage, white women, 
            in speaking not only for Negro freedom, but for
            the freedom of women. You were a runaway slave
            who made yourself free.
            </dialogue>
            <sp>SOJOURNER: </sp>
            <dialogue>
                And I wanted to vote.</dialogue>
            <sp>
                NARRATOR:
            </sp> 
            <dialogue>
                When they wouldn't let you sit on the platform
            because you were a Negro at the National Woman's
            Suffrage Convention in Akron, Ohio, in 1852, you
            sat wherre you are sitting now in the audience.
            </dialogue>
            <sp>
                SOJOURNER:
            </sp> 
            <dialogue>
                I did---until the going got hot, (SHE RISES) and
            the men speakers started baiting th ewomen, and
            talking about the women is weak, not strong as
            men nor smart as men, and they even have to be
            helped into carriages. 
                <action>
                (SHE COMES TO THE ROSTRUM)
                </action>
            Then I just walked up on that platform, sir, and
            told them men: "Nobody ever helped me into carriages,
            or over mud puddles, or give me any best place.
            Ain't I a woman? Look at me! Look at my arm!
            I have plowed and planted and agthered into barns,
            and no man could hear me, And ain't I a woman?
            I could work as much and eat as much as a man---
            when I could get it---and bear the lash as well---
            and ain't I a woman? I have had five chillum and
            seen 'em most all told off into slavery, and when
            I cried out with a mother's grief, none but Jesus..."
            </dialogue>
        </pg>
        <pg>
            <sp>
                (SOJOURNER):
            </sp> 
            <dialogue>
                "...heard---ain't I a woman? Thye talk about
            this thing in the head---intellect. What's that 
            got to do with woman's rights? If my cup won't
            hold but a pint and yourn holds a quart, wouldn't
            ye men be mean not to let me have my little half-
            measure full? If the first woman God made was
            strong enough to turn the world upside down all
            alone, I guess all us women together ought to be
            able to turn it back and get it right side up
            again. And now that they is asking to do it, the
            mens better let 'em."
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (SHE RETURNS TO HER PEW)
            </action>
            <sp>
                NARRATOR:
            </sp>
                <dialogue>
                    But it was alsmot three-quarters of a century
                before the country got around to giving you the
                vote, Sojourner Truth, before the 19th Amendment
                granting women's suffrage was passed.
                </dialogue>
                <sp>
                    SOJOURNER: 
                </sp>
                <dialogue>
                    It were finally passed---and about time, too!
                I took my freedom, but I didn't live long enough
                to vote.
                </dialogue>
                <dialogue>
                    Freedom! That was the first thing most Negroes
                were slaves. But some Negroes, even in the South,
                had never been slaves. Some were born free, some
                were given their freedo, and some ran away to
                freedom in the North. Among the great runaways
                was Frederick Douglas who escaped from a Maryland...
                </dialogue>
            
            
        </pg>
        <pg>
            <dialogue>
            ...plantaion in 1838, and devotes his life to
            fighting for freedom for all, and for full
            citizenship rights for all. IN his middle age:
            </dialogue>
                        <action>
                        (DOGULAS ENTERS, WHITE HAIREED,
                        WHITE BEARD, DIGNIFIED, IMPOSING)
                        </action>
            After Emancipation, after the Civil War was over,
            he made many speeches concerning the franchise.
            <sp>
                DOUGLASS:
            </sp>
            I see no chance of bettering the condition of the
            freedman until he shall cease to be merely a freed-
            man and shall become a citizen. I insist that
            there is no safety for him or anybody else in
            America outside the American government; to guard,
            protec, and maintain his liberty the freedmn
            should have the ballot; the liberties of the
            American people are dependent upon the abllot-
            box, the jury-box, and the cartridge-box.
            <sp>
                NARRATOR:
            </sp>
            <dialogue>
                And it took the cartridge-box to protect the
            rights of the freed Negroes in the early days of
            the Reconstruction. In 1867 Congress divided
            the South into five military districts, proclaimed
            universal suffrage, and placed federal marshalls
            at the polls to protect the Negroe's newly granted
            right to vote. This right was made pemanent by
            the passage in 1870 of the 15th Amendment to the
            Consitution of the United States. 700,000 Negroes
            were added to the voting rolls of the South, and
            many city and state offices were filled by the
            freedom. With Negroes in state legislatures,
            </dialogue>
        </pg>
        <pg>
            <sp>
                (NARRATOR):
            </sp>
            <dialogue>
                9 new state constitutions were drawn up with
                provisions for free public schools for all,
                civil rights for all, and no property qualifications
                for voting---the most progressive acts of laws
                the South had ever known, many of them remaining
                on the books until today.
                During the Reconstruction the Southern states
                sent 14 Negro Representatives and2 Senators of
                color to Washington. The first Repersentative
                was from Georgia, elected in 1869, Jefferson P.
                Long.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
               (LONG ENTERS TO STAND BESIDE NARRATOR.
                IN TURN, AS EACH MAN'S NAME IS CALLED,
                EACH ENTERS, ALTERNATIVELY AT LEFT OR
                RIGHT, TO FORM TWO LINE ON EACH SIDE 
                OF THE PLATFORM)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
            Then in 1871 South Carolina elected four Negro
            Congressman, Josepf H. Rainey.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER RAINEY)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                Roberto O. DeLarge.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER DeLARGE)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                Alonzo J. Rainer.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER RAINER)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                And Robert B. Elliott.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER ELLIOTT)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                That same year Alabama elected Benjamin S. Turner.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER TURNER)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                iN 1873 Mississippi elected John R. Lynch.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER LYNCH)
            </action>
        </pg>
        <pg>
            <sp>
                (NARRATOR)
            </sp>
            <dialogue>
            Alabama elected James T Rapier.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER RAPIER)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
            Florida elected Josiah T. Walls.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER WALLS)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                And South Carolina elected Richard H. Cain.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER CAIN)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
            That same year to the House of Representatives
            North Carolina elected John A. Hyman.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
            (ENTER NASH)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                That same year to the House of Representatives
                North Carolina elected John A. Hyman.
            </dialogue>
            <action>
                (ENTER HYMAN)
            </action>
            <dialogue>
                Alabama elected Jene Haralson.
            </dialogue>
            <action>(ENTER HARALSON)</action>
            <dialogue>
                And South Carolina elected Rovert Smalls.
            </dialogue>
            <action>(ENTER SMALLS)</action>
            <dialogue>
                The only Negro Senators in American history came
                at the very end of the Reconstruction period. The
                first, elected in 1870, was Hiram R. Revels.
            </dialogue>
            <action>(ENTER REVELS)</action>
            <dialogue>
                And the second in 1876 was Blanche K. Bruce.
            </dialogue>
            <action>(ENTER BRUCE)</action>
            <dialogue>
                Most of these men were as well qualified and as
                well educated as white officials of the times,
                and some better. Some were graduates of Oberlin
                or other leading Northern colleges. Elliot had
                studied abroad. Of those who served in Congress,
            </dialogue>
        </pg>
        <pg>
            <sp></sp>
            <dialogue></dialogue>
            <action></action>
            <sp>CAIN:</sp>
            <dialogue>
                I do not ask any legislation for the colored people
                of this country that is not applied to white people.
                All that we aks is equal laws, not equal legislation,
                and equal rights throughout the length and breadth
                of this land. We do not come here begging for our
                rights. We come here clothed in the garb of
                American citizenship. We come demanding our rights
                in the name of our children, in the name of our country.</dialogue>
        </pg>
    </body>
</root>
