<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="playSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
    <!-- mia: Sup Brett, sorry to peep in your XML but I just doctored up the schema
        errors you had. Let me know if you're wondering about something I changed -->
    <head>
        <title>Ballot and Me pages 8-12</title>
        <editor>Brett Meyer</editor>
    </head>
    <body>
        
        <!-- Mia: I put all of the page numbers self-closing tags, so you don't
         have to wrap the entire page in a <pg> element (:-->

        <pg n="9"/>
        
        <div1>  <!-- I made the schema so that <div1> will wrap the whole page, just because
        it'll be easier to change this element when we do some XSLT to get the page
         divisions separated when we turn this into HTML for the website.-->
            <sp>
                <speaker>(NARRATOR:)</speaker>  <!-- I think you might've accidentally
                                                   confused the <sp> element with the <speaker>
                                                    element, and I understand! The <sp> element
                                                  is written in the schema to wrap around the
                                                    entire section until the next speaker appears-->
                <dialogue>
                    
                    <p><location>Alabama</location> elected <person>James T Rapier</person>.</p> <!-- the <dialogue> needs <p> elements
                                                            to wrap around "paragraphs" of the dialogue
                                                            text, even if it's just one line of text
                                                        like these lines.-->

                <stage type="enter">
                (ENTER RAPIER)
                </stage>
            
                <p>
                <location>Florida</location> elected <person>Josiah T. Walls</person>.
                </p>
                    
                <stage type="enter"> 
                (ENTER WALLS)
                </stage>        <!-- you were putting <action> elements around the stage parts,
                             but instead, wherever theres little bits indicating action like
                            this, just wrap it in a <stage> element - and if the action involves
                            someone entering the scene, make it <stage type="enter">, but if
                            it involves anything other than someone entering (just general
                            actions), then make it <stage type="action">-->
                    
                <p>
                And <location>South Carolina</location> elected <person>Richard H. Cain</person>.
                </p>
                    
                <stage type="enter">
                (ENTER CAIN)
                </stage>
                    
                <p>
                <lb/>That same year to the House of Representatives
                <lb/><location>North Carolina</location> elected <person>John A. Hyman</person>.
                </p>   <!-- Wherever there's more than one line of dialogue, mark the 
                        beginnings of the lines with the self-closing attribute <lb/>
                        This way, when we make the website, we can make it look
                    accurate to the way the actual document looks, by indicating
                    where lines of text start inside <p> elements.-->
                    
                <stage type="enter">
                (ENTER HYMAN)
                </stage>
                    
                <p>
                <location>Alabama</location> elected <person>Jene Haralson</person>.
                </p>
                    
                <stage type="enter">
                (ENTER HARALSON)
                </stage>
                    
                <p>
                And <location>South Carolina</location> elected <person>Rovert Smalls</person>.
                </p>
                    
                <stage type="enter">
                (ENTER SMALLS)
                </stage>
                    
                <p>
                <lb/>The only Negro Senators in American history came
                <lb/>at the very end of the Reconstruction period. The
                <lb/>first, elected in <date when="1870">1870</date>, was <person>Hiram R. Revels</person>.
                </p>
                    
            <stage type="enter">(ENTER REVELS)</stage>
                    
            <p>
                And the second in <date when="1876">1876</date> was <person>Blanche K. Bruce</person>.
            </p>
                    
            <stage type="enter">(ENTER BRUCE)</stage>
                    
            <p>
                <lb/>Most of these men were as well qualified and as
                <lb/>well educated as white officials of the times,
                <lb/>and some better. Some were graduates of Oberlin
                <lb/>or other leading Northern colleges. <person>Elliott</person> had
                <lb/>studied abroad. Of those who served in Congress,
            </p>
            </dialogue>
       </sp>
  </div1>
        
        
        <pg n="10"/>
        
        
        <div1>
            <sp>
                <speaker>(NARRATOR:)</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>the Republican leader, James G. Blaine, said,
                        <lb/><q>"They were as a rule studious, earnest, ambitious
                        <lb/>men, whose public conduct would be honorable to
                        <lb/>any race."</q> Typical of the Negroes who serves in
                        <lb/>the House of Representatives at Washington was
                        <lb/><person>Richard H. Cain</person>, A.M.E. minister of <location>South Carolina</location>.
                        <lb/>Cain made a stirring speech in Congress regarding
                        <lb/>Civil Rights.
                    </p>
                </dialogue>
            </sp>
        
            <stage type="action">(CAIN STEPS FORWARD AND SPEAKS)</stage>
        
            <sp>
                <speaker>CAIN:</speaker>
            <dialogue>
                <p>
                <lb/>I do not ask any legislation for the colored people
                <lb/>of this country that is not applied to white people.
                <lb/>All that we aks is equal laws, not equal legislation,
                <lb/>and equal rights throughout the length and breadth
                <lb/>of this land. We do not come here begging for our
                <lb/>rights. We come here clothed in the garb of
                <lb/>American citizenship. We come <underline>demanding</underline> our rights
                <lb/>in the name of our children, in the name of our country.
                </p>
            </dialogue>
            </sp>
        </div1>
        
        
        <pg n="11"/> <!-- so here's were you left off, it would be "13 of 17" on
        the top left of the website, but it's page 11 on the actual typescript-->
        
        <!-- I started you off with an outline, hope that helps! Don't be afraid to
            message me for some help if you get stuck-->
        <div1>
            <sp>
                <speaker>NARRATOR:</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>During the Reconstruction in lesser degrees thereafter,
                        <lb/>many Negroes were active in state governments. For example, between 1868 and
                        <lb/>1896 Louisiana elected 32 state senators of color and 95 representatives.
                        <lb/>P. B. S. Pinchback was lieutenant-Governor and, in 1873, after the removal of
                        <lb/>the white incumbent, Pinchback became Acting-Governor of Louisiana. In Florida,
                        <lb/>Jonathan Gibbs, a Dartmouth graduate, became Secretary of State. And in South
                        <lb/>Carolina, the London-educated Francis L. Cardoso was from 1872 to 1876 the
                        <lb/>State Treasurer.                
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>But when federal troops were removed from the South in 1877 and
                        <lb/>Negro voters no longer had protection at the polls, reaction set in. The Ku Klux
                        <lb/>Klan began to ride. Voters werre intimidated, tarred and feathered, whipped,
                        <lb/>shot down. Black Codes were passed denying civil rights, and some states originated
                        <lb/>Grandfather Clauses which said that unless you or your parents had voted before the
                        <lb/>Civil War, you could not vote now --- which meant freedom were not eligible. Negro
                        <lb/>political power faded in the South. For a brief period during the rise of the
                        <lb/>Populist Party of farmers and poor whites, both Democrats and Reublicans again
                        <lb/>sought the Negro vote to keep The Populists from becoming powerful. then, from 1883 to
                        <lb/>1897, six Negroes were elected as Representatives to Washington. They were:
                    </p>
                    <p>from Virginia, JOhn M. Langston</p>
                    
                    <stage type="enter">(ENTER LANGSTON)</stage>
                    
                    <p>from South Carolina, Thomas E. Miller and George W. Murray:</p>
                    
                    <stage type="enter">(ENTER MILLER AND MURRAY)</stage>
                    
                    <p>And from North Carolina, James E. O'Hara, Henry P. Cheatham:</p>
                    
                    <stage type="enter">(ENTER O'HARA AND CHEATHAM)</stage>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>And the last of the Southern Representatives, George H. White of
                        <lb/>North Carolina, elected in 1897.
                    </p>
                    
                    <stage type="enter">(ENTER WHITE)</stage>
                </dialogue>
            </sp>
        </div1>
        
        
        <pg n="12"/>
        
        
        <div1>
            <sp>
                <speaker>NARRATOR(Ctd.)</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>When White completed his term in 1901, it was 27 years before
                        <lb/>another Negro went to Congress.
                        <lb/>One of the outstanding colored politicians was John M. Langston,
                        <lb/>Congressman from Virginia, founder of the Law School at Howard
                        <lb/>Univerity, and first presidnet of Virginia State College for
                        <lb/>Negroes. Widely known as a speaker, Langston, in an address at
                        <lb/>Saratoga, New York, in 1876, concerning the use of the ballot,
                        <lb/>said some wise things.
                    </p>
                </dialogue>
            </sp>
            
            <stage type="action">(LANGSTON COMES FORWARD)</stage>
            
            <sp>
                <speaker>LANGSTON:</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>Perhaps never in the history of our cuntry was there a time when
                        <lb/>the duty of the Americn voter to consider well and wisely what
                        <lb/>vote to cast, wht party to bring to power and support in pwer,
                        <lb/>was so imperative. In discharging our duty in this regard, while
                        <lb/>we are fearless, we should be impartial and just. Let us not
                        <lb/>make haste to condemn unduly, nor to accept without wise discrimi-
                        <lb/>nation the claim of any candidate or party. We are called upon
                        <lb/>as intelligent and earnest, patriotic and devoted citizens, to
                        <lb/>determine, each for himself, how votes given for the Democratic
                        <lb/>or Republicn party, will tend to sustain the dignity and power
                        <lb/>of the Government, and vonserve our free institutions under the
                        <lb/>Constitution. Eahc of us is held responsible to his own
                        <lb/>conscience, posterity and God for the wisdom, or folly displayed
                        <lb/>in exercising our suffrage - the most sacred, as it is the
                        <lb/>most valuable right which we possess on American soil.
                    </p>
                </dialogue>
            </sp>
            <sp>
                <speaker>NARRATOR:</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                        <lb/>Disfranchised in the South by state laws, trickery, or terror,
                        <lb/>no more Negro Congressman came from <Xout>there</Xout> <insert hand="LH">Dixie</insert> after Langston and
                        <lb/>White. But quietly behind the scenes, a practical-minded man
                        <lb/>of enormous political power emerged, consulted by national
                        <lb/>leaders North and South on all problems relating to the Negro,
                    </p>
                </dialogue>
            </sp>
        </div1>
    </body>
</root>
